Aiko Klostermann

Senior Software Engineer

2 Marina Blvd #30-06 Singapore 018987 ♠ +65 845 77 420 / +49 176 2746 9084 ⊠ jobs@aiko.dev https://aiko.dev in aikoklostermann

Summary

Having worked for a premium consultancy I was able to gather experiences from various projects, have worked with several different technology stacks which taught me how to pick up new technologies very quickly. I have worked in multiple microservice/distributed system architectures and have seem numerous different architectural patterns, have worked with multiple flavours of the agile SDLC and have seen what works and what doesn't.

Additionally I share my ideas and learnings by giving (keynote)talks and workshops at international conferences and writing articles which have been published by multiple publications.

Experience

ThoughtWorks

• Building high quality, maintainable, scalable and fault-tolerant software for various clients applying best practices like TDD, DDD, CI/CD, IaC, Pair Programming

5/2019 - present Senior Software Engineer, mostly Singapore.

- Java, Python, Led platform-wide performance testing and optimization effort(scale: >10 billion db rows)
 - Typescript, Took over the tech lead role of the team at the final stages of a project

Node.js, AWS, • Introduced client team to infrastructure as code(IaC)

Kubernetes

- Azure, Docker, Onboarded multiple batches of new hires by giving lectures on topics like Clean Code design concepts like SOLID principles, Pair Programming, TDD, etc.
 - Organised and facilitated a weekly infrastructure engineering study group

6/2017 - 4/2019 Software Engineer, mostly Bangalore, India.

- Java, Python, Introduced the client to the concept of CI and importance of a comprehensive test coverage
- Django, AWS, o Joined a project with nearing deadline due to of my expertise in Python which led to us Docker delivering ahead of time after all
 - Led the Data/AI/ML enthusiasts group in ThoughtWorks India with > 130 members

6/2016 - 5/2017 Graduate Software Engineer, Hamburg, Germany.

- Java, Python, Introduced client to neural networks & increased order prediction accuracy by 18% to 82%
- AWS, Tensorflow Owned cloud migration effort and managed to be the first team to go-live on cloud infrastructure University of Applied Sciences Hamburg

3/2014 - 8/2014 Teaching Assistant for Programming II, Hamburg, Germany.

Taught advanced Java/Programming concepts including Multithreading, Generics and Inner classes

Additional Achievments

- (Keynote)Speaker at various international conferences
- Have had my articles published by DataQuest, FinTechNews, Thoughtworks.com i.a.
- PROMOS Scholarship recipient for overall academic results

Education

9/2012 - 5/2016 University of Applied Sciences Hamburg, B.Sc. Computer Science.

Thesis Project: Convolutional Neural Networks on Mobile Devices Grade: 4.0/4.0

8/2014 - 12/2014 The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Semester Abroad.

Skills

Languages Java, Python, Javascript & Typescript, C, C++, HTML, CSS, HCL

Frameworks Spring {Boot}, Django, Flask, Node.js, React, ReactNative, Angular, TensorFlow

DevOps/Infra Terraform, Cloudformation, Docker, Kubernetes, Linux/Unix Shells, Ansible, AWS, Azure

Others PostgreSQL, MongoDb, REST, GraphQL, gRPC, Protobuf, Apache Kafka, distributed sys-

tems/microservice architecture, Jupyter Notebook, TDD, Performance optimization